Does it matter?
We'll never turn to it anyway.
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
What the hell is that?
Cut him down.
Rival gangs, guardian angels, or the goddamn Salvation Army.
Get him off the street and off the front page.
They say it was just one guy.
Or a creature.
What's some asshole in the costume?
Yeah.
This guy did deliver us one of the city's biggest crime lords.
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
Understand?
No way to bury it now.
Maybe so, but they're still Judge Faden.
Got Faden covered.
Okay, what about this bat they're babbling about?
Even if these guys will swear in court to being thrashed by a giant bat,
we've got Falcone at the scene.
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests.
This bat character gave us everything.
Okay, let's do it.
Bats are nocturnal.
Bats may be, but even for billionaire playboys,
three o'clock is pushing it.
Price for leading a double life, I fear.
Your theatrics made an impression.
Metricality, deception.
Powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come,
it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
Polo, for instance.
Not learning polo, Alfred.
Strange injuries and non-existent social life.
These things beg the question as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money?
What does someone like me do?
Oh, drive sports cars, date movie stars, buy things that are not for sale.
Who knows, Master Wayne?
You start pretending to have fun, you might even have a little buy accident.
Sir, we have a situation.
All right.
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night.
Heavily damaged, all crew missing.
Probably dead.
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon. It's a microwave emitter. It's designed for desert warfare.
But it...
It looks like somebody turned it on.
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
The damage to the ship was catastrophic. The weapon itself is...
Missing?
Yeah.
I've seen another one.
He's done something the police have never done.
You can't take the law into your own hands.
At least he's getting something done.
Bruce, help me out here.
Huh?
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
And now the cops want to bring him in, so what does that tell you?
They're jealous.
Sir, the pool is for decoration and your friends do not have swimwear.
Well, they're European.
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
It is not a question of money.
You see, I'm buying this hotel and setting some new rules about the pool area.
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
Bruce?
Rachel?
I'd heard you were back.
What are you doing?
Uh, just swimming.
Wow, it is good to see you.
You were gone a long time.
I know.
How are things?
Same.
Job's getting worse.
Can't change the world on your own.
What choice do I have?
When you're too busy swimming.
Rachel, all of...
All this, it's not me.
It's inside. I am.
Bruce, deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
But it's not who you are underneath.
It's what you do that defines you.
Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
Not at all. He cut his wrists.
Probably looking for the insanity plea.
I learned if anything should happen.
Of course. Better safe than sorry.
Yeah, Dr. Crane, I can't take it anymore. It's all too much.
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
A couple of days of this food will be true.
What do you want?
I want to know how you're going to convince me to keep my mouth shut.
About what? You don't know anything.
I know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
I know about your experiments with the inmates of your nuthouse.
See, I don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
And look, those goons you used, I own the muscle in this town.
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months.
So, whatever he's planning, it's big.
And I want it.
Well, I already know what he'll say.
That we should kill you.
Even he can't get me in here.
Not in my town.
Would you like to see my mask?
I use it in my experiments.
He's probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
With these crazies, he can't stand it.
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
They scream and they cry.
What is your game now?
He's not faking. Not that one.
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved to the secure wing at Arkham.
I can't treat him here.
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
It's a start. Your partner was at the docks with Falcone.
Oh, he Moonlights is a low-level enforcer.
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
Why? What about the other half?
Flask knows.
He won't talk.
He'll talk to me.
Mission to love set up a massive task force to catch you.
He thinks you're dangerous.
What do you think?
I think you're trying to help.
But I've been wrong before.
I have kids to feed.
Do I don't like falafel?
Where were the other drugs going?
I never knew. I don't know. I swear to God.
Swear to me!
I don't know. I never knew. Never.
They went to some guy for a couple of days before they went to the dealer.
Why?
There was something. Something else in the drugs. Something hidden.
I never went to the drop off point. It was in the nearest. Cops only go there when they're in force.
Do I look like a cop?
That's what I'm talking about. What's your problem with it?
It shouldn't exist. This ship left Singapore with 246 containers but arrived with 247.
So I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
Listen, counselor, we don't want to know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.