Does it matter? We'll never turn to it anyway.
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
What the hell is that?
Cut him down.
Unacceptable.
I don't care if it's rival gangs, guardian angels, or the goddamn Salvation Army.
Get him off the street and off the front page.
They say it was just one guy. Or a creature.
Or some asshole in a costume.
Yeah.
This guy did deliver us one of the city's biggest crime lords.
No one takes the bar into their own hands in my city.
Understand?
No way to bury it now.
Maybe so, but there's still Judge Faden.
We've got Faden covered.
Okay, what about this bat they're babbling about?
Even if these guys will swear in court to being thrashed by a giant bat,
we've got Falcone at the scene.
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
Okay, let's do it.
Bats are not carnal.
Bats may be, but even for billionaire playboys, three o'clock is pushing it.
Price for leading a double life, I fear.
Your theatrics made an impression.
Theatricality, deception.
You have powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come,
it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
Polo, for instance.
I'm not learning polo, Alfred.
Strange injuries, a non-existent social life.
These things beg the question
as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
What does someone like me do?
Drive sports cars, date movie stars,
Movie stars?
Buy things that are not for sale?
Who knows, Master Wayne?
You start pretending to have fun,
you might even have a little buy accident.
Sir, we have a situation.
All right.
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night.
Heavily damaged, all crew missing.
Probably dead.
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon.
It's a microwave emitter.
It's designed for desert warfare.
It looks like somebody...
turned it on.
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
The weapon itself is, um...
Missing?
Yeah.
That's pretty good.
Nice car.
We should see another one.
He's done something the police have never done.
You can't take the law into your own hands.
At least he's getting something done.
Bruce, help me out here.
Well, the guy dresses up like a bat.
Clearly has issues.
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
And now the cops want to bring him in.
So what does that tell you?
They're jealous.
Sir, the pool is for decoration and your friends do not have swimming rooms.
Well, they're European.
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
It is not a question of money.
You see, I'm buying this hotel and setting some new rules about the pool area.
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
Bruce?
Rachel?
I'd heard you were back.
What are you doing?
Uh, just swimming.
Wow. It is good to see you.
You haven't gone a long time.
I know. How are things?
Same.
Job's getting worse.
Can't change the world on your own.
What choice do I have?
When you're too busy swimming.
Rachel, all of...
all this...
It's not me.
It's...
Inside, I am...
I am more.
Come on, Bruce, come!
We have some more Italian leaves to buy!
Bruce...
Deep down, you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
But it's not who you are underneath.
It's what you do that defines you.
I'm sorry.
are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
In a couple of days of this food,
it'll be true.
What do you want? I want to know
how you're gonna convince me to keep my mouth
shut. About what? You don't
know anything. I know you don't want
the cops to take a closer look at the drugs
they seized. I know
about your experiments with the inmates of
your nut house. See,
I don't go into business with a guy without finding out
his dirty secrets.
And those goons you used,
I own the muscle in this town.
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months.
So whatever he's planning, it's big.
And I want it.
Well, I already know what he'll say.
That we should kill you.
Even he can't get me in here.
Not in my town.
Would you like to see my mask?
I use it in my experiments.
I'm probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
But these crazies, you can't stand it.
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
They scream and they cry.
Which is your game now?
Well, he's not faking. Not that one.
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved to the secure wing at Arkham.
I can't treat him here.
Storm's coming.
Scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone
It's a start
Your partner was at the docks with Falcone
Oh, he moonlights as a low-level enforcer
They were splitting the shipment in two
Only half went to the dealers
Why? What about the other half?
Flass knows
He won't talk
He'll talk to me
Mission to Love set up a massive task force to catch you
He thinks you're dangerous.
What do you think?
I think you're trying to help.
But I've been wrong before.
Come on, I ain't got a way.
I have kids to feed.
What, you don't like falafel?
Where were the other drugs going?
I never knew.
I don't know.
I swear to God.
Swear to me.
I don't know.
I never knew. Never.
They went to some guy for a couple of days before they went to the dealer.
Why?
There was something.
Something else in the drugs.
Something hidden.
What?
I never went to the drop-off point.
It was in the narrows.
Cops only go there when they're in force.
Do I look like a cop?
No!
This is the one I'm talking about.
What's your problem with it?
It shouldn't exist.
The ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
So I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
Listen, Counselor, we don't want to know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.