my garden only before breakfast
how little man and i am
the devil you're not the devil protection protection for them
are you so desperate to fight criminals that you lock yourself in to take them
on one at a time actually they were uh
I counted six, Mr. Wayne.
How do you know my name?
The world is too small for someone like Bruce Wayne to disappear, no matter how deeply chooses to sink.
Who are you?
My name is merely Ducard, but I speak for Raz Al Ghul, a man greatly feared by the criminal underworld.
A man who can offer you a path.
Makes you think I need a path.
Someone like you is only here by choice.
You have been exploring the criminal fraternity, but whatever your original intentions, you have become truly lost.
On what path can Ra's al Ghul offer?
The path of a man who shares his hatred of evil and wishes to serve true justice.
The League of Shadows.
The Vigilantes.
No, no, no.
The Vigilante is just a man lost in the scramble for his own gratification.
he can be destroyed or locked up.
But more than just a man,
if you devote yourself to an ideal,
and if they can't stop you,
then you become something else entirely.
Legend, Mr. Wayne.
Tomorrow you will be released.
If you are bored of brawling with petty thieves
and want to achieve something,
there is a rare blue flower that grows on the eastern slopes.
Pick one of these flowers.
If you can carry it to the top of the mountain,
You may find what you were looking for in the first place.
And...
...feelate the fears in others.
Ready to begin.
Stay.
Death does not wait for you to be raped.
Death is not considered warfare.
And make no mistake.
Here you face death.
You did so.
Ah!
I'll set the bone and...
...take him for an x-ray later.
Very good, sir.
I'm very sorry, sir.
I've talked.
Don't worry, that's fine.
Took quite a fall, didn't we, Master Bruce?
And why did we fall, Bruce?
So we can learn to pick ourselves up.
You know why they attacked you, don't you?
They were afraid of you.
Afraid of me?
All creatures feel fear.
Even the scary ones.
Especially the scary ones.
I got something to show you.
It's time to get up.
Maybe.
Did you build this train, Dad?
Gotham's been good to our family.
But the city's been suffering.
People less fortunate than us have been enduring very hard times.
So we build a new, cheap public transportation system to unite the city.
And at the center, Wayne Tower.
Is that where you work?
No, I work at the hospital.
I lead the running of our company to much better men.
Better?
Well, more interested men.
I just needed some fresh air.
A little bit of opera goes a long way.
Right, Bruce?
Come on.
Let's go.
Wallace.
Joy.
I'm a bastard.
That's fine.
Take it easy.
Here you go.
That's fine.
Now just take it and go.
I said you were...
Hey!
I need you!
Shut up!
Says your fathers.
We'll be watching the Empire.
When you grow up, it'll be waiting for you.
It was my fault, Alfred.
I made the deed to fear.
No, no, no, no, no.
If my handguns get...
It was nothing that you did.
it was him.
So what?
So you still feel responsible for your parents' death?
My anger outweighs my guilt.
Come.
You have learned to bury your guilt with anger.
I will teach you to confront it
and to face the truth.
You know how to fight six men.
We can teach you how to engage 600.
You know how to disappear.
We can teach you to become truly invisible.
Invisible.
Abhi!
The ninja understands that invisibility is a matter of patience and agility.
Always mind your surroundings.
Ninjutsu employs explosive powders.
As weapons?
Or distractions?
Theatricality and deception are powerful agents.
You must become more than just a man in the mind of your opponent.
Who is he?
He was a farmer, and he tried to take his neighbor's land and became a murderer.
Now he is a prisoner.
What will happen to him?
Justice.
Crime cannot be tolerated.
Criminals thrive on the indulgence of society's understanding.
Your parents' death was not your fault.
It was your father's.
Change the fact that your father failed to act.
The man had a gun.
Would that stop you?
I've had training.
The training is nothing.
The will is everything.
The will to act.
You haven't beaten me.
You've sacrificed sure footing for a killing stroke.
Rub your chest.
Your arms will take care of themselves.
You're stronger than your father.
You didn't know my father.
But I know the rage that drives you.
That impossible anger strangling the grief
until the memory of your loved one is just poisoning your veins.
And one day you catch yourself wishing the person you loved had never existed,
so you'd be spared your pain.
I wasn't always here in the mountains, taken from me.
Like you, I was forced to learn there are those without decency
who must be fought without hesitation, without pity.
Your anger gives you great power,
but if you let it, it will destroy you,
as it almost did me.
What stopped it?
Vengeance.
That's no help to me.
Why could you not avenge your parents?
Will you be heading back to Princeton
after the hearing, sir,
or can I persuade you to stay on for a day or two?
I'm not heading back at all.
You don't like it, do you?
I like it fine.
They just don't feel the same way.
I've prepared the master bedroom.
No.
My room will be fine.
With all due respect, sir, Wayne Manor is your house.
No, Alfred, it's my father's house.
Your father is dead, Mr. Wayne.
This place is a mausoleum.
If I have my way, I'll pull the damn thing down brick by brick.
This house, Master Wayne, has sheltered six generations of your family.
Why do you give a damn, Alfred? It's not your family.
I give a damn because a good man once made me responsible
for what was most precious to him in our world.
Miss Doris has offered her to drive you to the hearing.
She probably hopes to talk you out of going.
Should I just bury the past out there with my parents, Alfred?
I wouldn't presume to tell you what to do with your past, sir.
Just know that there are those of us who care about what you do with your future.
You haven't given up on me yet.
Never.
Alfred still keeps the condensed milk on the top shelf.
Doesn't he notice you're tall enough to reach now?
Well, have us die hard, I guess.
Never used to stop us anyway.
No, I didn't. How's your mom?
She misses this place. So do I.
Yeah. But it's nothing without the people who made it what it was.
Now there's only Alfred.
And you?
I'm not staying, Rachel.
You're just back for the hearing.
Bruce, I don't suppose there's any way to convince you not to come.
Someone had this proceeding. It should stand for my parents.
We all loved your parents, Bruce.
What Chill did is unforgivable
Then why's your boss letting him go?
In prison, he shared a cell with Carmine Falcone
He learned things, and he will testify in exchange for early parole
Rachel, this man killed my bear
I cannot let that pass, and I need you to understand that, please
The Depression hit working people like Mr. Chill hardest of all
His crime was appalling, yes, but it was motivated not by greed, but by desperation
and given the 14 years already served
as well as its extraordinary level of cooperation
with one of this office's most important investigations,
we strongly endorse his petition for early release.
Mr. Chiu?
Not a day goes by that I don't wish I could take back what I did.
I'm sure I was desperate, like a lot of people back then,
but they don't change what I did.
I gather there is a member of the Wayne family here today.
Has he got anything to say?
We don't need to see this.
The DA couldn't understand why Judge Faden insisted on making the hearing public.
Falcone paid him off to get chill out in the open.
Maybe I should be thanking them.
You don't mean that.
What if I do, Rachel?
My parents deserve justice.
You're not talking about justice.
You're talking about revenge.
Sometimes they're the same.
No, they're never the same, Bruce.
Justice is about harmony.
Revenge is about you making yourself feel better.
That's why we have an impartial system.
Well, your system is broken.
You care about justice?
Look beyond your own pain, Bruce.
This city is rotting.
They talk about the Depression as if it's history, and it's not.
Things are worse than ever down here.
Falcone floods our streets with crime and drugs,
preying on the desperate, creating new Joe chills every day.
Falcone may not have killed your parents, Bruce.
He's destroying everything that they stood for.
You want to thank him for that? Here you go.
We all know where to find him.
But as long as he keeps the bad people rich and the good people scared,
no one will touch him.
If good people like your parents will stand against injustice, they're gone.
What chance does Gotham have when the good people do nothing?
I'm not one of your good people, Rachel.
What do you mean?
All these years I wanted to kill him.
Now I can't.
I would be ashamed of you.
You look in the tabloids, Mr. Wayne.
No gun. I'm insulted.
You could have just sent a thank you note.
I didn't come here to thank you.
I came here to show you that not everyone at Gotham is afraid of you.
Only those who know me, kid.
Look around you.
You'll see two consulmen.
A union official, a couple off-duty cops, and a judge.
Now, I wouldn't have a second's hesitation of blowing your head off right here and right now in front of him.
Now, that's power you can't buy.
That's the power of fear.
I'm not afraid of you.
Because you think you've got nothing to lose.
But you haven't thought it through.
You haven't thought about your lady friend down in the DA's office.
You haven't thought about your old butler.
Bang!
People from your world have so much to lose.
Now you think, because your mommy and your daddy got shot,
you know about the ugly side of life, but you don't.
You've never tasted desperate.
You're Bruce Wayne, the Prince of Gotham.
You'd have to go a thousand miles to meet someone who didn't know your name.
So don't come down here with your anger, trying to prove something to yourself.
This is a world you never understand, and you always fear.
what you don't understand.
Yeah, you got spirit, kid.
I'll give you that.
More than your old man, anyway.
In the joint, Chill told me, uh,
told me about the night he killed your parents.
He said your father begged for mercy.
Like a dog.
Should've did better.
For what?
Your jacket.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
Let me have some nice coat.
He carefully sees you with that.
They're gonna come looking for me.
Who?
Everyone, among the criminals, did you start to pity them?
The first time I stole so that I wouldn't starve, yes, I lost many assumptions about the simple nature of right and wrong.
And when I traveled, I learned the fear before a crime and the thrill of success.
But I never became one of them.
Fool. What the hell do I care what your name is? You're a criminal.
What was your friend, Yuen?
Tell that to the guy who owned these.
You've traveled the world to understand the criminal mind, conquer your fears.
The criminal is not complicated.
What you really fear is inside yourself.
You fear your own power.
You fear your anger.
The drive to do great or terrible things.
Now, when he inwards, breathe.
To conquer fear, you must become fear.
You must bask in the fear of other men.
And men fear most what they cannot see.
You have to become a terrible thought.
You have to become an idea!
You have to lead these men.
But first, you must demonstrate your commitment to...
I avoid!
...but to fight criminals, this man is a murderer.
He's married.
By whom? Corrupt bureaucrats?
Criminals mock society's laws.
You know there's better than most.
are prepared to do what is necessary to defeat evil.
Or would I be leading these men?
To strike at the heart of criminality.
Gotham's time has come.
Like Constantinople or Rome before it.
The city has become a breeding ground for suffering and injustice.
It is beyond saving and must be allowed to die.
This is the most important function of the league.
It is one we performed for centuries.
I will tell him you said he's alive.
Master Wayne, you've been gone a long time.
Yes, I have.
You look very fashionable.
Apart from the mud.
Were you coming back to Gotham for long, sir?
As long as it takes.
I'm going to show the people of Gotham their city doesn't belong to the criminals.
In the Depression, your father nearly bankrupted Wayne Enterprises combating poverty.
He believed that his example could inspire the wealthy of Gotham to save their city.
Did it?
In a way, their murder shocked the wealthy and the powerful into action.
People need dramatic examples to shake them out of apathy,
and I can't do that as Bruce Wayne.
As a man, I'm flesh and blood.
I can be ignored, I can be destroyed, but as a symbol,
as a symbol, I can be everlasting.
What symbol?
Something.
I assume that as you're taking on the underworld,
this symbol is a persona to protect those you care about from reprisals.
You thinking about Rachel?
Hey, Rita, I was thinking of myself.
You told anyone I'm coming back?
I just couldn't figure.
The legal ramifications are bringing you back from the dead.
Dead?
You've been gone seven years.
You had me declared dead?
Well, actually, it was Mr. Earl. He's taking the company public.
He wanted to liquidate your majority shareholding.
Those shares are worth quite a bit of money.
Well, it's a good thing I left everything to you, then.
Quite so, sir.
And you can borrow the rolls, if you like.
Just bring it back with a full tank.
In my opinion, Mr. Zaz is as much a danger to himself as to others.
And prison is probably not the best environment for his rehabilitation.
Dr. Crane?
Oh, Mr. Oz.
You really think a man who butchers people for the mob doesn't belong in jail?
Well, I would hardly have testified to that otherwise when I missed Oz.
This is the third of Carmine Falcone's thugs you had declared insane and moved into your asylum.
Well, the work offered by organized crime must have an attraction to the insane.
Or the corrupt.
Mr. Finch, I think you should check with Miss Dawes here
just what implications your office has authorized her to make.
If any.
What are you doing, Rachel?
What are you doing, Carl?
Looking out for you.
Falcone is half the city.
Bought and paid for.
How can you say that?
Because as much as I care about getting Falcone,
I care more about you.
That's sweet.
Bless you, Pat.
They get some.
They nest somewhere in the grounds.
Don't you mind, Doc? I'm bringing in the shipments.
We are paying you for that.
Maybe money isn't as interesting to me as Favis.
I am more than aware that you are not intimidated by me, Mr. Falco.
But you know who I'm working for.
And when he gets here...
He's coming to Gotham?
Yes, he is.
And when he gets here, he's not going to want to hear that you have endangered our operation
just to get your thugs out of a little jail time.
Who's bothering you?
There's a girl at the DA's office.
We'll buy a Roth, not this one.
Idealist, huh?
Well, there's an answer to that, too.
No, we are showing very healthy growth in these sectors.
I don't think that Thomas Wayne would have viewed heavy arms manufacture as a suitable cornerstone for our business.
It's 20 years ago.
I think after 20 years we can allow ourselves to stop thinking about what Thomas Wayne would have done.
Good morning, Mr. Earl's office.
Oh, yes, he's confirmed for the dinner tomorrow evening.
Good morning.
I'm here to see you, Mr. Earl.
Name?
Bruce Wayne.
Thomas would probably not have taken the company public,
but that is what we as responsible managers are going to do.
Jessica.
Jessica, where are you?
I want to answer your phone.
It's Wayne Enterprises, Mr. Earl. I'm sure they'll call back.
Bruce, you're supposed to be dead.
Sorry to disappoint.
I need you to take a look at this.
Have you seen him yet?
Who?
Wayne.
He's been over the news.
He's back.
I'm sure you realize I can't stop.
Big machine, too many wheels turning.
We're going public.
I understand.
And I'll be handsomely rewarded for my shares.
I'm not looking to interfere.
I am looking for a job.
Oh?
I just want to get to know the company that my family built.
Any ideas where you would start?
Applied Sciences caught my eye.
Fox Department.
I let him know you're coming.
You look like him.
Yeah, your dad.
You're the only one left of the Wayne family.
This is where you belong.
Welcome home.
Environmental procedures, defense projects,
consumer products,
all prototypes.
Not in production.
On any level whatsoever.
None.
What did they tell you this place was?
They didn't tell me anything.
Earl told me exactly what it was
and sent me down here.
Dead end.
Place to keep me from causing the board any more trouble.
You were on the board?
When your father ran things.
You knew my father?
Oh yeah, helped him build his train.
Oh, here we are.
Kevlar utility harness,
gas powered magnetic grapple gun,
the 350 pound test monofilament.
Wonderful project, your dad's train.
Rided it right into Wayne town,
along with the water and power utilities.
I gotta make Wayne Tower the unofficial senator of Gotham City.
Of course, Earl had to go to the rot. Here we are.
Nomex survival suit for advanced infantry.
Kevlar bi-weave, reinforced joints.
Terror-resistant.
This sucker will stop a knife.
Bulletproof.
Anything but a straight shot.
Why didn't they put it into production?
Bean counters didn't think a soldier's life was worth 300 grand.
So, what's your interest in it, Mr. Wayne?
I wanna borrow it for, uh, Spelunky.
Spreling.
Yeah, you know cave diving?
You're expecting to run into much gunfire in these caves?
Look, I'd rather Mr. Earl didn't know about me borrowing.
Mr. Wayne, the way I see it, all this stuff is yours anyway.
You good? Give it a try.
Charming. At least you'll have company.
This must be the lowest foundation of the South East Wing.
In the Civil War, your great-great-grandfather was involved in the Underground Railroad,
secretly transporting three slaves to the North.
And I suspect these cabins came in handy.
I can see everything arrived from down here, sir. Thank you very much.
Part of this cow from Singapore...
...by a dummy corporation.
Indeed. And then quite separately, we place an order through a Chinese company for these.
Put it together ourselves.
Precisely.
There'll have to be large orders to avoid suspicion.
How large?
Say, 10,000.
Well, at least we'll have spares.
Yes.
Don't suppose you want a taste.
Just keep offering, thinking maybe someday you'll get wise.
There's nothing wise in what you do, Flash.
Well, Jimbo, you don't take the taste.
Makes us guys nervous.
I'm not a rat.
In a town that's been, who's there to write to anyway?
Don't turn around.
Carmine Falcone brings a shitloads of drugs every week.
Nobody takes him down. Why?
He's paid up with the right people.
What will it take to bring him down?
Leverage on Judge Faden.
And a DA right enough to prosecute.
Rachel Dawes.
Who are you?
Watch for my side.
You're just one man.
What the hell was that?
Just some nut.
What is it today? More spelonky?
No. Today it's base jumping.
Base jumping?
Is that like parachuting?
Kinda. Do you have any lightweight fabrics?
You know, I think I have just a thing.
It's called memory cloth.
Notice anything?
Regularly flexible.
But put a current through it, molecules realign, it becomes rigid.
What kind of shapes can you make?
It can be tailored to fit in any structure based on a rigid skeleton.
Too expensive for the Army?
I don't think they ever tried to market it to the billionaire's belonging base dumping crowd.
Look, Mr. Fox.
Yes, sir?
If you're uncomfortable...
Mr. Wayne, if you don't want to tell me exactly what you're doing when I'm asked, I don't have to lie.
But don't think of me as an idiot.
What's that?
Want a tumbler?
It was built as a bridging vehicle.
During combat, two of these would jump over a river, throwing caves.
And over here on the throttle, flip that open and throttle up.
This will boost you into a rampless jump.
No, no!
Disengaged.
We never could get the damn bridge to work, but this baby works just fine.
No!
So what do you think?
Does it come in black?
I need you at the docks Thursday.
Problems?
I don't want any trouble with the last shipment.
Sure.
We're on the street is you gotta beef with somebody in the DA's office.
That's not right.
And that there's a fat prize waiting for anybody willing to do anything about it.
So what's your point, Mr. Flass?
Have you seen the girl?
It's a cute little assistant DA.
I think it's a little bit too much heat to bring down, maybe.
Even for this town.
Never underestimate Gotham City.
People get mugged coming home from work every day of the week.
Sometimes, sometimes things just go bad.
Sir, the problem with the graphite, sir, the next 10,000 will be up to specifications.
At least they gave us a discount.
Quite.
In the meantime, sir, may I suggest you try to avoid landing?
On your head.
White bats lost away.
That's frightened me.
This time my enemies shared my dread.
What is this?
Continue.
Looks fine out there.
Bears, they go straight to the dealers.
Yeah, and the rabbits go to the man in the narrows.
What's the difference?
Ignorance is bliss, my friend.
Don't burden yourself with these secrets of scary people.
Hey, it's Dice.
I wouldn't be too sure of that.
Gangs, guardian angels, or the goddamn Salvation Army.
Get them off the street and off the front page.
They say it was just one guy or a creature.
What's some asshole in the costume?
This guy did deliver us one of the city's biggest crime lords.
No one takes the law into their own hands in my city.
Understand?
No way to bury it now.
Maybe so, but they're still Judge Faden.
Got Faden covered.
Okay, what about this bat they're babbling about?
Even if these guys will swear in court to being thrashed by a giant bat, we've got Balconi at the scene.
Drugs, prints, cargo manifests. This bat character gave us everything.
Okay, let's do it.
Bats are nocturnal.
Bats may be, but even for billionaire playboys, three o'clock is pushing it.
Price for leading a double life, I fear.
Your theatrics made an impression.
Metricality, deception.
They're powerful weapons, Alfred. This is a good start.
If those are to be the first of many injuries to come, it would be wise to find a suitable excuse.
Polo, for instance.
I'm not learning polo, Alfred.
Strange injuries and non-existent social life.
These things beg the question as to what exactly does Bruce Wayne do with his time and his money.
What does someone like me do?
Drive sports cars.
Take movie stars.
Buy things that are not for sale.
Who knows, Master Wayne?
You start pretending to have fun, you might even have a little by accident.
Sir, we have a situation.
All right.
The Coast Guard picked up one of our cargo ships last night.
Heavily damaged, all crew missing.
Probably dead.
The ship was carrying a prototype weapon.
It's a microwave emitter.
It's designed for desert warfare, but it...
It looks like somebody, um, turned it on.
It uses focused microwaves to vaporize the enemy's water supply.
The damage to the ship was catastrophic.
The weapon itself is, um...
Missing?
Yeah.
I've seen another one.
He's done something the police have never done.
You can't take the law into your own hands.
At least he's getting something dumb.
Bruce, help me out here.
Well, a guy who dresses up like a bat clearly has issues.
But he's put Falcone behind bars.
And now the cops want to bring him in, so what does that tell you?
They're jealous.
Sir, the pool is for decoration and your friends do not have swim room.
Well, they're European.
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
It is not a question of money.
You see, I'm buying this hotel and setting some new rules about the pool area.
I think the Batman deserves a medal.
And a straitjacket to pin it on.
Bruce?
Rachel?
I heard you were back.
What are you doing?
Uh, just swimming.
Wow, it is good to see you.
You were gone a long time.
I know. How are things?
Same. Job's getting worse.
Can't change the world on your own.
What choice do I have?
When you're too busy swimming.
Rachel, all of... all this...
It's not me. It's... inside. I am...
Bruce, deep down you may still be that same great kid you used to be.
But it's not who you are underneath.
It's what you do that defines you.
Dr. Crane, thanks for coming.
Not at all. He cut his wrists.
Probably looking for the insanity plea.
But if anything should happen...
Of course. Better safe than sorry.
Yeah, Dr. Crane, I can't take it anymore. It's all too much.
The walls are closing in. Blah, blah, blah.
Not a couple of days of this food.
It'll be true.
What do you want?
I want to know how you're going to convince me to keep my mouth shut.
About what?
You don't know anything.
I know you don't want the cops to take a closer look at the drugs they seized.
I know about your experiments with the inmates of your nuthouse.
See, I don't go into business with a guy without finding out his dirty secrets.
You know, those goons you used.
I own the muscle in this town.
Now, I've been bringing your stuff in for months.
So whatever he's planning, it's big.
And I want it.
Well, I already know what he'll say.
That we should kill you.
Even he can't get me in here.
Not in my town.
Would you like to see my mask?
I use it in my experiments.
He's probably not very frightening to a guy like you.
With these crazies.
He can't stand it.
So when did the nut take over the nut house?
They scream and they cry.
Which is your game now?
He's not faking. Not that one.
I'll talk to the judge and see if I can get him moved to the secure wing at Arkham.
I can't treat him here.
The scum is getting jumpy because you stood up to Falcone.
It's a start. Your partner was at the docks for the Falcone.
Oh, he Moonlights is a low level enforcer.
They were splitting the shipment in two. Only half went to the dealers.
Why? What about the other half?
The Flask knows.
He won't talk.
He'll talk to me.
Mission Love set up a massive task force to catch you.
He thinks you're dangerous.
What do you think?
I think you're trying to help.
But I've been wrong before.
Man, I have kids to feed.
Do I don't like falafel?
Where were the other drugs going?
I never knew. I don't know. I swear to God.
Swear to me!
I don't know. I never knew. Never.
They went to some guy for a couple of days before they went to the dealer.
Why?
There was something. Something else in the drugs.
Something hidden. What?
I never went to the drop-off point.
It was in the narrows. Cops only go there when they're in force.
Do I look like a cop?
Stop it!
What am I talking about?
What's your problem with it?
It shouldn't exist.
This ship left Singapore with 246 containers, but arrived with 247.
So I'm guessing there's something I'm not supposed to find in there.
Listen, counselor, we don't want to know what's in Mr. Falcone's crate.
Things are working a little differently now.
Open it up.
It's you, isn't it?
Everybody's been talking about you.
Don't get in here!
The other kids won't believe me.
Bit of all traces.
Gonna torch the whole place.
All right.
It's your birthday.
This was so much more potent.
Hallucinogen.
Weaponized in aerosol form.
You have been hanging out in the wrong clubs, Mr. Wayne.
I called Mr. Fox when your condition worsened after the first day.
I analyzed your blood, isolating the receptor compounds and the protein-based catalyst.
I'm not going to understand any of that.
Not at all.
I just wanted you to know how hard it was.
Bottom line, I synthesized an antidote.
Could you make more?
Are you planning on gassing yourself again, Mr. Wayne?
You know how it is, Mr. Fox.
You're out at night looking for kicks.
Someone's passing around the weaponized to loosen the jets.
I'll bring what I have.
The antidote should inoculate you for now.
Alfred, always a pleasure.
Lucius, you sure you don't want to come in?
I have to get back.
I just wanted to leave this.
Thank you.
Rachel?
Looks like someone's been burning the candle at both ends.
Must have been quite an occasion.
It is my birthday.
I know.
I'm sorry I can't come tonight. I was just dropping off your present.
You've got better plans?
My boss has been missing for two days,
which in this town means that I should probably start by looking at the bottom of the river.
Rachel.
Rachel Doss.
Who authorized that?
Get Crane down there right now. Do not take no for an answer.
Call Dr. Lehman. Tell him we'll need our own assessment on the judge's desk by morning.
What's wrong?
It's Falcone. Dr. Crane moved him to Arkham Asylum on suicide watch.
You're going to Arkham now. It's in the Narrows, Rachel.
You enjoy your party, Bruce.
Some of us have work to do.
You be careful.
With Master Wayne, the guests will be arriving.
Keep them happy until I arrive.
Tell them that joke, you know.
What's a big shot like you doing in a place like this?
I need some information.
The Wayne Antwerp 47B-1-M-E.
It's a microwave emitter.
It was designed to vaporize an enemy's water supply.
Rumor was they tested dispersing water-based chemical agents into the air,
but isn't that illegal?
I want all the information on the development of this project.
All data, files, backup disks on my desk right away.
Did you lose one?
I'm merging your department with archives.
This is most irregular. I have nothing further to add to the report I filed with the judge.
I have questions about your report.
Such as?
Isn't it convenient for a 52-year-old man who has no history of mental illness
to suddenly have a complete psychotic breakdown just when he's about to be indicted?
Well, as you can see for yourself, there is nothing convenient about his symptoms.
What's Scarecrow?
Patients suffering delusional episodes often focus their paranoia on an external tormentor,
usually one conforming to Jungian archetypes.
In this case, a Scarecrow.
He's drugged?
Psychopharmacology is my primary.
I'm a strong advocate.
Outside, he was a giant.
In here, only the mind can grant you power.
You enjoy the reversal.
I respect the mind's power over the body.
It's why I do what I do.
I do what I do to keep thugs like Falcone behind bars and not in therapy.
I want my own psychiatric consultant to have full access to Falcone, including blood work.
Find out what exactly you put him on.
First thing tomorrow, then.
Tonight.
I've already paged Dr. Laman at County General.
As you wish.
This way, please.
There's something I think you should see.
This is where we make the medicine.
Perhaps you should have something to clear your head.
What do we do?
What anyone do, or comes around.
You want the cops here?
At this point, they can't stop us.
But the Batman has a talent for disruption.
Force him outside, the police will take him down.
What about her?
She hasn't got law.
I give her a concentrated dose.
The mind can only take so much.
Go the things they say about him
Can you really fly I heard he can disappear?
Well, we'll find out
Won't we he isn't here right now. I'll go in now. I'll be right behind you sir
What's on the way?
Hey
Dusing dogs in we get it down to the medics they can't help her but I can
Talks in hidden inside Falcone's drugs and then dumping into the water supply
Why? What was he planning?
I don't know.
Was he working for Falcone?
He meant to someone else. Someone worse.
I need to get her the antidote before the damage becomes permanent.
How long does she have?
Not long.
What is that?
We gotta go.
I'll get my car.
I brought mine.
Yours.
I gotta get me one of those.
He is in a vehicle.
Make it color.
It's a black...
Tank!
Stay calm.
You've been poisoned.
I'm on him.
Notify the water company.
There's got to be a way of isolating the areas.
No, you don't understand.
They put it all in.
They must have been at this for weeks.
The captain's entire water supplies laced with it.
Why haven't we felt the effects?
Must be a compound that has to be absorbed through the lungs.
How do you feel?
Why did you bring me here?
If I hadn't, your mind would now be lost.
You were poisoned.
This...
This Dr. Crane...
Rest.
Gordon has Crane.
I'm sorry.
Gordon has cream.
Is Sergeant Gordon your friend?
I don't have the luxury of friends.
I'm going to give you a sedative.
You'll wake up back at home.
When you do, get these to Gordon.
And Gordon alone trusts no one.
What are they?
The antidote.
One for Gordon to inoculate himself, the other for mass production.
Mass production.
Cream was just a pawn.
We need to be ready.
When you told me your grand plan for saving Gotham,
The only thing that stopped me from calling the men in white coats
was when you said that it wasn't about thrill-seeking.
It's not.
What would you call that?
Damn good television.
It's a miracle no one was killed.
I didn't have time to observe the rules of the road, Alfred.
You're getting lost inside this monster of yours.
I'm using this monster to help other people just like my father did.
But Thomas Wayne helping others wasn't about proving anything to anyone,
including himself.
It's Rachel, Alfred.
She was dying.
She's downstairs sedated.
I need you to take her home.
Well, we both care for Rachel, sir.
But what you're doing has to be beyond that.
It can't be personal.
Well, you're just vigilante.
Is Fox still here?
Yes, sir.
We need to send these people away now.
Those are Bruce Wayne's guests out there, sir.
You have a name to maintain.
I don't care about my name.
It's not just your name, sir.
It's your father's name.
And it's all that's left of him.
Don't destroy.
Happy birthday, Bruce.
Thank you.
How'd the stock offering go?
The price is soared.
Who was buying?
All kinds of funds and brokerages.
It's a bit technical.
The key thing is, our company's future is secure.
What was the plan, Crane?
How were you going to get your toxin into the air?
Who were you working for, Crane?
Happy birthday, Bruce.
Well, thank you.
Thanks.
And thank you for that item.
You're welcome.
You're welcome. I know you put it to good use.
I already have.
How long would it take to manufacture on a large scale?
Weeks. Why?
Somebody's planning to disperse the toxin using the water supply.
Water supply won't help you disperse an inhaler.
Unless you have a microwave emitter powerful enough to vaporize all the water in the mains.
A microwave emitter like the one-way Enterprise is just misplaced.
Misplaced?
We're all just fired for asking too many questions about it.
I need you to go back to Wayne Enterprises right now and start making more of that antidote.
I think the police are going to need as much as they can get their hands on, okay?
My security clearance has been revoked.
That won't stop a man like you now, would it?
I suppose not.
Bruce, there's somebody here you said we must meet.
Now, am I pronouncing this right?
Mr. Raz al Ghul?
No, Raz al Ghul.
I watched him die.
But is Waraz Al Ghul immortal?
Are his methods supernatural?
More cheap parlor tricks to conceal your true identity, Raz.
Surely a man who spends his nights scrambling over the rooftops of Gotham
wouldn't begrudge me dual identities.
He warned you about compassion.
The quarrel is with me. You let these people go.
Welcome to explain the situation to them.
Everyone?
Everybody?
I want to thank you all for coming here tonight and drinking all of my booze.
There's a thing about being a Wayne that you're never short of a few freeloaders like yourselves to fill up your mansion with.
So here's to you people.
Thank you.
That's enough.
Awesome.
I'm not finished.
To all of you, uh, all you phonies, all of you two-faced friends, you sycophantic suck-ups who smile through your teeth at me, please leave me in peace.
Please go. Stop smiling. It's not a joke. Please leave. The party's over. Get out.
The apple has fallen very far from the tree, Mr. Wayne.
Amusing, but pointless.
None of these people have longed to live.
Your antics at the asylum have forced my hand.
So Crane was working for you?
His toxin is derived from the organic compound found in our blue flowers.
He was able to weaponize it.
He's not a member of the League of Shadows?
Of course not. He thought our plan was to hold the city to ransom.
But really, you are gonna release Crane's poison on the entire city.
Then watch Gotham tear itself apart through fear.
You're gonna destroy millions of lives.
Only a cynical man would call what these people have lie this way.
Crime, despair.
This is not how man was supposed to live.
The League of Shadows has been a check against human corruption for thousands of years.
We sacked Rome, loaded trade ships with plague rats, burned London to the ground.
ground every time a civilization reaches the pinnacle of its decadence we return to restore
the balance gotham isn't beyond saving give me more time there are good people here you are
defending a city so corrupt we have infiltrated every level of its infrastructure when i found
you in that jail you were lost but i believed in you i took away your fear and i showed you a path
You are my greatest student.
It should be you standing by my side saving the world.
I'll be standing where I belong.
And the people of Gotham.
No one can save Gotham.
When a forest grows too wild, a purging fire is inevitable and natural.
Tomorrow the world will watch in horror as its greatest city destroys itself.
The movement back to Harmony will be unstoppable this time.
You attacked Gotham before.
Of course.
Over the ages, our weapons have grown more sophisticated.
With Gotham, we tried a new one, economics.
But we underestimated certain of Gotham's citizens,
such as your parents.
Gunned down by one of the very people they were trying to help.
Create enough hunger and everyone becomes a criminal.
Their deaths galvanized the city into saving itself,
and Gotham has limped on ever since.
We are back to finish the job.
At this time no misguided idealists will get in the way.
Like your father, you lack the courage to do all that is necessary.
If someone stands in the way of true justice,
you simply walk up behind them and stab them in the heart.
We never did learn to mind your surroundings.
Justice is balance.
You burned my house and left me for dead.
Consider us even.
No one comes out. Make sure.
How many from maximum security?
Every one of them. Serial killers, rapists...
Get them to raise the bridges. We don't want any getting off the island.
Yeah, I'll raise the bridges, but I get every available unit out here to catch the homicidal maniacs that are running loose out there.
Come on.
I hope you're not a member of the fire brigade.
Faster, wait!
What is the point of all those push-ups if you can't even lift a bloody log?
Or maybe you'd like to see some excessive force.
Hey, man!
Man with your gun.
With residents curious at the unprecedented show
of police strength to round up the enrave,
the situation is...
Oh, lady!
We're about to raise these bridges.
Officer, I'm a Gotham City District Attorney.
Let me pass.
Somebody here to see you.
What are you doing here?
A mutual friend sent me with this counter-x-creant toxin.
Hopefully you won't need it.
Unless he's got some way of getting that crap into the air.
All right, last one across.
I'd better get you off the island before they raise the bridges.
Patrolman!
Stop!
I can't find my mom.
Gentlemen, time to spread the word.
And the word turns.
Spiking.
Right there.
That water main is right under the Narrows.
The Narrows is tearing itself to pieces.
This is just the beginning.
If they hit the whole city with Toxin,
There's nothing to stop Gotham tearing itself apart from mass panic.
How are they gonna do that?
They'll be using the train.
The monorail follows the water mains to the central hub beneath Wayne Tower.
If they get their machine into Wayne Station,
it'll cause a chain reaction that'll vaporize the entire city's water supply.
Covering Gotham in this poison.
I'm gonna stop him from loading that train, but I may need your help.
What do you need?
Can you drive stick?
Nothing to fear, but fear itself.
I can hear the hell!
They will save us.
Luke, don't peek.
Mrs. Gordon, prepare to lower the bridge.
You could die. At least tell me your name.
It's not who I am underneath, but what I do that defines me.
Bruce?
You took my advice about theatricality a bit? Literally.
It ends here.
But you and the police, maybe. My fate, however, lies with the rest of Gotham.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a city to destroy.
I can't beat two of your pawns.
As you wish.
GPS online. It's in 100 yards.
I seem to remember firing you. You did. I got another job. Yours.
Who's authority?
Batman may have made the front page, but Bruce Wayne got pushed to page 8.
Bruce Wayne?
What makes you think you can decide who's running Wayne Enterprises?
Well, the fact that I'm the owner.
What are you talking about?
The company went public a week ago, and I bought most of the shares.
Through various charitable foundations and trusts and so forth.
Look, it's all a bit technical, but the important thing is that my company's future.
Right, Mr. Fox?
Right you are, Mr. Wayne.
Didn't you get the memo?
I didn't tell you, Rachel.
No, no, Bruce. I'm sorry.
The day that Chill died, I...
I said terrible things.
But true things.
I was a coward with a gun.
Justice is about more than revenge, so...
Thank you.
I never stopped thinking about you.
About us.
When I heard you were back, I...
I started to hope.
Then I found out about your mask.
Your real face is the one that criminals now fear.
A man I loved.
A man who vanished.
He never came back at all.
Prove me wrong, you know.
About what?
Father would be very proud of you.
Just like me.
What will you do?
Rebuild it.
Just the way it was, brick for brick.
Just the way it was, sir?
Yeah, why?
I thought this might be a good opportunity for improving the foundations.
In the southeast corner.
Precisely, sir.
I couldn't find any mob bosses.
Well, Sergeant.
Oh, it's Lieutenant now.
You really started something.
Bent cops running scared.
Hope on the streets.
But?
The Narrows is lost.
I still haven't picked up Crane or half the inmates of Arkham that he freed.
We will.
We can bring government.
What about escalation?
Escalation.
We start carrying semi-automatics, they buy automatics.
We start wearing Kevlar.
They buy armor-piercing rounds.
And...
And you're wearing a mask.
Jumping off rooftops.
Take this guy.
Arm robbery, double homicide.
Got a taste for the theatrical, like you.
Leaves a calling card.
I never said thank you.